<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oliver Mills</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Oliver Mills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Scraping and Word Clouds</title>
      <link>/2019/03/09/web-scraping-and-word-clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/03/09/web-scraping-and-word-clouds/</guid>
      <description>What better way to guage the opinion of the general public than trawling through online comments on articles. The visuals below were created by scraping the comments from an article about the proposed capital gains tax in NZ and using R to do some basic text mining and data visualisation.
This wordcloud above shows the overall sentiment of the comments, seperating each word into positive (green) or negative (red) groupings based on the users comments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notable Trees in Auckland, NZ</title>
      <link>/2019/02/17/notable-trees-in-auckland-nz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/17/notable-trees-in-auckland-nz/</guid>
      <description>Here’s an interactive map of ‘notable’ trees in the Auckland region I created this using Leaflet, a powerful mapping package in R. Take your time to scroll around the Auckland region and click on the green points to see what kind of special trees you have in your neighbourhood! (datasource)
The inspiration for this post came from Isaac Bain’s tutorial where he used freely available data to map the DOC huts around NZ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Work Experience 3.5+ years experience working as a data and information analyst for the Ministry of Business, Innovation and Employment. In this role I helped roll out a number of data initiatives aimed at increasing the data maturity of the NZ Companies Office. These initiatives ranged from creating a cross-registry data catalogue, undertaking data quality and governance excercises and working with stakeholders to design analytical solutions to solve real business problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Film Photos</title>
      <link>/2019/02/16/film-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/16/film-photos/</guid>
      <description>A few film photos from my recent travels in Eastern Europe. All photos taken on a Canon A-1. </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>